C.H. Dexter Company Records
© 2002 University of Connecticut
- Series IV: Financial Records, 1854-1981
  - Subseries B: Records of C.H. Dexter Stock, 1917-1981
    - Ledger/Tabbed Index, 1957-1963 (Box 34)
  - Subseries C: Tax Documents, 1920-1952
    - International Tax Records, 1952 (Box 6:168)
    - Tax Claim Forms, 1941-1949 (Box 6:169)
    - Tax Records, 1920 (Box 6:170)
    - Tax Records, 1920-1923 (Box 6:171)
    - Oversized Tax Records, 1920-1922 (Box 17:321)
    - Oversized Tax Records, 1922-1944 (Box 17:322)
  - Subseries D: Financial Reports, 1914-1976
    - Internal Audit, 1914 (Box 6:172)
    - Report and Accounts, 1925-1927 (Box 6:173)
    - Report and Accounts, 1928-1931 (Box 6:174)
    - Bound Audit Reports, 1937-1950 (Box 6)
    - Bound Audit Reports, 1951-1960 (Box 6)
    - Bound Audit Reports, 1961-1963 (Box 7)
    - Bound Audit Reports, 1964-1966 (Box 7)
    - Audit, 1967 (Box 7:175)
    - Audit, 1968 (Box 7:176)
    - Audit, 1969 (Box 7:177)
    - Audit, 1969-1970 (Box 7:178)
    - Audit, 1970-1971 (Box 7:179)
    - Audit, 1971-1972 (Box 7:180)
    - Audit, 1972-1973 (Box 7:181)
    - Audit, 1973-1974 (Box 7:182)
    - Audit, 1974-1975 (Box 7:183)
    - Audit, 1975-1976 (Box 7:184)
    - Midland Industrial Finishes Co. Special Customer Report, 1964-1966 (Box 17:323)
    - Midland Industrial Finishes Co. Special Customer Report, 1964-1966 (Box 17:324)
- Series V: Publications, 1900-1993
  - Subseries A: Internal Histories, 1900-1988
    - History of Dexter, by Bob Archibald
      - Copy 1, 1988 (Box 8:185)
      - Copy 2, 1988 (Box 8:186)
      - Notes and Sources, "Early Years", 1958-1988 (Box 8:187)
      - Notes and Drafts, "Intro" and "Early Years", undated (Box 8:188)
      - Notes and Drafts, "The First Paper Mill", 1900-1979 (Box 8:189)
      - Notes and Drafts, "The Coffin Branch", 1961-1963 (Box 8:190)
      - Notes and Drafts, "Dexter Family", 1955-1988 (Box 8:191)
      - Notes and Drafts, "Long Fiber Papers", 1944-1979 (Box 8:192)
      - Notes and Drafts, "Fortune 500 Co.", 1983-1988 (Box 8:193)
      - Notes and Drafts, "The Seventies", 1988 (Box 8:194)
      - Notes and Drafts, "Homes of Dexter and Coffin", undated (Box 8:195)
      - Notes and Drafts, "Fires and Floods", 1955-1984 (Box 8:196)
      - Notes and Drafts, "Chronology", 1982 (Box 8:197)
      - Notes and Drafts, "Profit-Sharing", undated (Box 8:198)
      - Interviews and Contacts, 1988 (Box 8:199)
      - Other notes and sources, 1964-1977 (Box 8:200)
    - History of the Dexter Corporation 1767-1967
      - David L. Coffin, 1967 (Box 8:201)
    - History of Dexter's Long Fiber Paper Development
      - Fay Osborne, 1979 (Box 8:202)
  - Subseries B: Publications by Dexter Corporation, 1970-1975
    - "Corporate Identity," handbook on corporation trademark, undated (Box 8:203)
    - Dexter Trademark Guide, undated (Box 8:204)
    - Corporate Profile pamphlets, 1970-1973 (Box 8:205)
    - Posters/Stock Performance, undated (Box 18:325)
    - Brochures/divisions of Dexter Corporation, undated (Box 8:206)
    - Brochure/Chemical Coatings Corporation, undated (Box 8:207)
    - Brochure/Mogul, undated (Box 8:208)
    - T.R. Wirtz meat casing publication, 1975 (Box 8:209)
    - Letterhead and business card, undated (Box 8:210)
  - Subseries C: Newsletters, 1955-1987
    - Scoop, Dexter Corporation, 1966-1987 (Box 8:211)
    - Dexstar Family Scoop, 1955-1966 (Box 8:212)
    - Dexter People, 1982-1984 (Box 8:213)
    - Medical Products Examiner, 1983 (Box 8:214)
    - Fiscal Fitness, 1981 (Box 8:215)
    - Hysol Division, Horizon, 1984 (Box 8:216)
  - Subseries D: Other Publications, 1914-1993
    - Chirnside Mill, 1976-1984 (Box 8:217)
    - "Superior Facts" booklet, 1931 (Box 8:218)
    - Newspaper and magazine clippings, 1962-1963 (Box 8:219)
    - Government Reports, 1914-1916 (Box 8:220)
    - FTC Reports, 1915 (Box 8:221)
    - Report/Product Study, 1940 (Box 8:222)
- Series VI: Advertising and Product Samples, c. 1880-1992
  - Subseries A: Advertisements, 1956-1988
    - Paper and Tissue Ads, undated (Box 9:223)
    - Oversized Paper and Tissue Ads, undated (Box 18:326)
    - Anniversary Logo Design, 1992 (Box 9:224)
    - Brochure Layout Plan, 1988 (Box 9:225)
    - Print Ads, 1956-1967 (Box 9:226)
    - Product Sample/Toilet Tissue Ads, undated (Box 9:227)
    - Product Sample/Papers, undated (Box 9:228)
    - Advertisement ledger, undated (Box 9:229)
  - Subseries B: Advertising Booklets/XTRA, undated
    - Nos. 1-15, undated (Box 9:230)
    - Nos. 16-25, undated (Box 9:231)
    - Nos. 26-35, undated (Box 9:232)
    - Nos. 36-50, undated (Box 9:233)
    - Nos. 51-64, undated (Box 9:234)
    - Nos. 65-70, undated (Box 9:235)
  - Subseries C: Product Samples, undated, c. 1880-1932
    - "Manifold" Paper (ads and sample booklet), c. 1890 (Box 9:236)
    - "Dexstar" paper and pricelist, 1932 (Box 9:237)
    - "Star Bristol" Papers, c. 1880 (Box 9:238)
    - "Foudrinier" tissue papers, undated (Box 9:239)
    - "Embossed" tissue papers, undated (Box 9:240)
    - "Silver Tissue", undated (Box 9:241)
    - "Sta-Brite" tissue, undated (Box 18)
    - "Dextex" Fabric, undated (Box 18:327)
    - Envelopes, undated (Box 9:242)
    - Loose Items/ "Manila" Paper Sample Binders 1 and 2, undated (Box 9:243)
    - Cover samples, undated (Box 10:244)
    - Packaged "Medicated Manila" Toilet Tissue, undated (Box 10:245)
    - Packaged "Medicated Manila" Toilet Tissue, undated (Box 10:246)
    - Unwrapped "Star Medicated Manila" Toilet Tissue, undated (Box 10:247)
    - Unwrapped "Star Medicated Manila" Toilet Tissue, undated (Box 10:248-249)
    - "Star Medicated Manila" Toilet Tissue Packaging, undated (Box 10:250)
    - Corporate File Folder Plan, undated (Box 18:328)
    - Tea Bag Samples, undated (Box 16)
    - Binder 1/ "Dexstar Carbonizing Tissue", undated (Box 11)
    - Binder 2/ "Dexstar Manifold Tissue", undated (Box 11)
    - Binder 3/ Idea Book, undated (Box 11)
- Series VII: Photographs and Memorabilia, 1950-1998
  - Subseries A: Photographs, 1966-1995
    - Long Range Planning Meetings, 1966-1981 (Box 12:251)
    - Long Range Planning Meetings, 1981-1984 (Box 12:252)
    - Blue Album No. 1, undated (Box 12:253)
    - Blue Album No. 2, undated (Box 12:254)
    - Red Album/Royal Visit at Chirnside Mill, 1972 (Box 12:255)
    - Red Album/Royal visit at Chirnside Mill/Loose Items, 1972 (Box 12:256)
    - Photographs/Portraits from board meetings, undated (Box 12:257)
    - Portraits of Dexter CEOs, undated (Box 12:258)
    - Photographs of Worth Loomis, 1989-1995 (Box 12:259)
    - Photographs of Fay Osborne, undated (Box 12:260)
    - Photographs of Board Members, 1967-1968 (Box 12:261)
    - Photographs of employees, undated (Box 12:262)
    - Photographs of Corporate Headquarters, Windsor Locks, CT, undated (Box 12:263)
    - Photographs of Dexter Corporation Physical Plants, undated (Box 12:264)
    - Photographs of Chirnside Mill plant, undated (Box 12:265)
    - Early Photographs, undated (Box 12:266)
    - Photographs of Windsor Locks Canal, undated (Box 12:267)
    - Photographs of Dexter Old Flour Mill, undated (Box 12:268)
    - Photographs of flood damage, undated (Box 12:269)
    - Photographs for 200th Anniversary Booth, undated (Box 12:270)
    - Photographs of Dexter Product Displays, undated (Box 12:270a)
    - Other photographs, undated (Box 12:270b)
    - Sketches and Photographs/Dexter Administrators, undated (Box 18:329)
    - Portrait/David Coffin, undated (Box 18:330)
    - Panoramic Photographs/Connecticut River, undated (Box 13)
    - Framed Photographs, undated (Box Art Storage)
  - Subseries B: Films, 1972-1973
    - "Dexter at Chirnside" copy 1, 1972 (Box 14)
    - "Chirnside Royal Visit", 1973 (Box 14)
    - "Sequence II", 1973 (Box 14)
  - Subseries C: Longevity Tokens, 1967
    - 200th Anniversary Commemorative Bowl, 1967 (Box 14)
    - Dexter Belt Buckle, undated (Box 14)
  - Subseries D: Dexter Memorabilia, 1978-1990
    - Embossed Paper Weights, undated (Box 14)
    - Cost-determining apparatus, undated (Box 14:271)
    - Engraved Plates of CEOs, undated (Box 14:272)
    - Unframed Prints, 1978 (Box 14:273)
    - Awards Banquet Program, 1990 (Box 14:274)
  - Subseries E: Other Memorabilia, 1950-1998
    - Windsor Locks Heritage Calendar, 1998 (Box 14:275)
    - Eisenhower Day Guest Pass, 1950 (Box 14:276)
    - World's Fair, Chicago Guidebook, 1950 (Box 14:277)
- Series VIII: Affiliated Businesses, 1848-1936
  - Subseries A: Connecticut River Company, 1848-1926
    - Charter, undated (Box 15:278)
    - Land Records, 1868-1870 (Box 15:279)
    - Proposals for Improvements and Additions, 1898 (Box 15:280)
    - Correspondence, 1848-1904 (Box 15:281)
    - Receipts, 1869-1901 (Box 15:282)
    - Stock Reports, 1895 (Box 15:283)
    - Stock Transfer Documents, 1912-1921 (Box 15:284)
    - Water Usage Reports, 1902-1925 (Box 15:285)
    - Court Cases, 1868-1884 (Box 15:286)
    - Publication about Canal, undated (Box 15:287)
    - Connecticut River Transfer Documents, 1911-1913 (Box 15:288)
    - Mergers and Consolidations, 1923-1926 (Box 15:289)
    - Oversized Documents, 1894 (Box 18:331)
    - River Log, 1902 (Box 35)
    - River Log, 1903 (Box 36)
    - River Log, 1906 (Box 37)
    - River Log, 1907 (Box 38)
    - River Log, 1908 (Box 39)
    - River Log, 1911 (Box 40)
    - River Log, 1915 (Box 41)
    - River Log, 1921 (Box 42)
    - River Log, 1922 (Box 43)
    - River Log, 1924 (Box 44)
    - Ledger, 1913-1926 (Box 45)
  - Subseries B: Northern Connecticut Securities Company, 1913-1926
    - Legal Documents, Correspondence and Records, 1913-1926 (Box 15:290)
  - Subseries C: Northern Connecticut Power Company, 1905-1936
    - Northern Connecticut Power Project Scrapbook/Loose Items, 1927-1936 (Box 15:291)
    - Northern Connecticut Power Project Scrapbook/Letters and Publications, 1927-1936 (Box 15:292)
    - Oversize Documents, 1936 (Box 18:332)
    - Journal/Stockholders' and Directors' Minutes, 1905-1926 (Box 46)
    - Journal/Stockholders' and Directors' Minutes, 1926-1935 (Box 47)
    - Power Project Scrapbook, 1927-1936 (Box 48)
  - Subseries D: Northern Connecticut Light & Power Company, 1904-1926
    - Loose Items/Stock Ledger (Vol 52), undated (Box 15:293)
    - Ledger/Stock Certificates (1-100), undated (Box 49)
    - Ledger/Stock Certificates (1-200), undated (Box 50)
    - Ledger/Stock Certificates (201-400), undated (Box 51)
    - Ledger/Stock Certificates (399-600), undated (Box 52)
    - Ledger/Stock Certificates (701-900), undated (Box 53)
    - Stockholders'/Directors' Meetings, 1904-1910 (Box 54)
    - Stockholders'/Directors' Meetings, 1911-1926 (Box 55)
  - Subseries E: Stafford Springs Aqueduct Company, 1885-1926
    - Loose Items/Ledger (Vol 56), 1888-1918 (Box 15:294)
    - Ledger, 1885-1921 (Box 56)
    - Ledger, 1921-1926 (Box 57)
    - Ledger/ Capital Stock Certificates, undated (Box 58)
    - Ledger/ Preferred Stock Certificates, undated (Box 59)
  - Subseries F: Coffin Realty Company, 1909-1926
    - Correspondence, Files and Reports of J. S. Allen, 1918-1926 (Box 15:295)
    - Correspondence/S. R. Benjamin & Company, 1916-1923 (Box 15:296)
    - Correspondence/A.D Coffin and H.R. Coffin, 1917-1923 (Box 15:297)
    - Correspondence/Chapman and Cleorland, 1909-1918 (Box 15:298)
    - Other Correspondence/E-P, 1916-1924 (Box 15:299)
    - Other Correspondence/T-W, 1913-1923 (Box 15:300)
    - Legal Documents, 1915-1926 (Box 15:301)
    - Property Records, 1919-1923 (Box 15:302)
    - Bankbook, 1916-1920 (Box 15:303)
    - Checks and Vouchers, 1919 (Box 15:304)
    - Checks and Vouchers, 1920 (Box 15:305)
    - Checks and Vouchers, 1921 (Box 15:306)
    - Checks and Vouchers, 1922 (Box 15:307)
    - Checks and Vouchers, 1923 (Box 15:308)
    - Checks and Vouchers, 1924-1925 (Box 15:309)
    - Ledger/Journal and Balance Sheets, 1926 (Box 15:310)
    - Map/Windsor Locks Property Lines, undated (Box 18:333)
    - Map/Windsor Locks Property Lines, undated (Box 18:334)
  - Subseries G: Grove Cemetery Documents, 1859-1925
    - Grove Cemetery Documents, 1859-1925 (Box 15:311)
    - Grove Cemetery Record Book, 1845-1891 (Box 66)
    - Thompsonville Water Company Minutes/Directors' Meetings, 1884-1916 (Box 60)
    - Thompsonville Water Company Minutes/Directors' Meetings, 1916-1926 (Box 61)
    - Windsor Locks Canal Company Minutes/Stockholders' and Directors' Meetings, 1936-1974 (Box 62)
    - Windsor Locks Canal Company Minutes/Stockholders' and Directors' Meetings, 1975-1979 (Box 63)
    - Windsor Locks Canal Company Oversize Documents, 1849 (Box 18:335)
    - Somers Electric Company Minutes/Directors' Meetings, 1915-1926 (Box 64)
    - Ledger/Chemical Coatings Corporation, undated (Box 65)